[The Unclouded Soul]
[Episode 23]
Why are you hurt again?
I just accidentally scratched it.
Where did you get scratched?
In the bamboo grove.
You look very pale.
I haven't been
sleeping well these days.
I just met Luoluo.
He told me everything.
Hmm.
Support Admin Watch on
kissasia.cam or kisskh.org
If there's nothing else,
get some rest early.
Don't you know your body
can't take
being injured over and over again?
I can handle it.
Why must you be so stubborn?
What choice do I have?
As the Demon Lord,
if I have no power to protect everyone,
and I can't even fulfill
my responsibilities,
I'm just a Demon Lord in name only.
So you know you're the Demon Lord.
Only with you around
do the demons exist
Small injuries accumulate and will
become serious problems.
If something happens to you,
what will happen to them?
But I can't always
let you risk yourself for me.
Why can't we share the burden together?
That would only make me feel more guilty.
So I choose to do things my way.
Fine.
Do it your way then.
I'm tired.
You may leave.
Xiao Ming.
M-My Lord.
Please don't be angry.
I'm just really too tired.
I haven't slept for days.
Can we let Xiao Mu
come out to do the search?
Sure.
Rest up.
I'll take over.
My Lord, don't worry.
We'll find a solution eventually.
Xiao Mu.
You've read so many books
and ancient texts,
do you know any good methods
to relieve depression?
But,
depression is something
only humans without power
would have.
Demons don't need to know about this.
No, no.
I mean,
demons have better solutions.
We can
practice cultivation diligently,
or
go hunting,
or take some magical medicine,
or if all else fails,
even having a fight
to let off steam works.
Anyway,
as long as we find
the cause of the depression,
that should solve it.
What if it's just because
you're trying too hard
to fulfill your duty,
you end up hurting someone you love?
Then it should be the other person
who's feeling depressed.
No, I misspoke.
You're right.
Go on.
Then apologize to her,
or just keep being good to her.
Just make sure she knows how you feel.
So how should I treat her well?
I only know how to treat you well,
My Lord.
As for others...
It's pointless asking you.
Xiao Ming.
Before His Lordship recovers his power,
when he wants someone to talk to,
you should be the one to keep him company.
Making His Lordship happy
is harder than cultivation.
Now you've got my attention.
My Lord.
Loving someone
means sharing with her.
No matter what happens,
you have to bear it together,
instead of enduring it alone.
But what if I just
don't want her to share my burden?
Love
is supporting each other
and sharing responsibilities.
How do you know
she would be upset
if you share your burden?
How do you know
she wouldn't be upset
if you decide to do things alone?
Xiao Ming, where did you learn
all this nonsense from?
This is nothing.
While looking through ancient texts,
I happened
to read a couple of plays
from the human realm
and picked up a few lines.
So you haven't
been looking for a solution at all,
but reading plays instead?
Xiao Ming is right for that.
Mr. Wu Huan,
do you still hold a grudge?
It's not your place to lecture me.
Let's make a bet.
Let's have a contest.
If you win, I'll let you go.
If you lose,
you'll be at my mercy.
Who do you think you are?
What about it?
Fine.
Let's have a try.
You lost.
Your power
has improved so quickly.
Did you train so hard
just to harm your own kind?
Hong Ye became the Demon Lord
because of his protection of demons
and compassion for all beings.
So even if he lost his power,
he would still have everyone's support.
Cultivation is also about the mind.
I hope you let go of your obsession soon.
Don't preach to me.
Do what you want with me—
be it murder or torture.
Hey!
As the Demon Lord,
I have my responsibilities.
Though I've lost my power,
no one knows
Demons' Valley better than I do.
I don't want to hide.
But I can't always let you
risk yourself for me.
That would only make me feel more guilty.
So I choose to do things my way.
Why is this only half written?
Is there
any clue in the book?
Very few records talk about
the Heart-Burning Incantation.
I've only figured out that
My Lord is unable
to use the power in his body
because his heart meridian is damaged,
but his power is still in there.
Really?
Of course.
See for yourself if you don't believe me.
Most of these ancient demon texts
are fragments—
disconnected and incoherent.
I've been piecing them together for days.
I don't even know
if I can piece them together.
You can.
I'm sure you'll figure it out.
Have you seen Hong Ye?
Stop asking me questions.
My head is already a mess.
Okay. I'll leave you alone.
You keep working on it.
You're smart enough to figure it out.
I...
Why don't you do it?
Don't run away.
You're not getting it!
Where did he go?
Disappearing all over again.
I told you that you can't do it.
Xiao Yao.
I think
my wound
needs new dressing.
The medicine is inside the room.
You know that.
Go change it yourself.
I was wrong
last night.
I made you worry.
I know.
Since I lost my power,
I've been suppressing my anxiety.
I always wanted to do something
but feared you'd bear too much burden.
For a hundred years,
I've shouldered many things alone.
I got used to it.
I wanted so badly to protect you,
yet feared you getting hurt.
So I chose the stupidest way.
Are you not saying anything?
Not even a sentence?
Please say something.
Your wounds hurt me too!
Don't you know that?
Put yourself in my shoes.
If I were the one getting hurt—
always getting hurt—
how would you feel?
I...
Don't be angry anymore.
I am angry.
Are you still angry?
All right.
It's my fault.
I promise you.
From now on,
I will share
everything with you,
okay?
In the future too.
Forever.
♪ Cliffside streams flow, pine scents
fill my sleeves as I sleep ♪
♪ What year will cranes return?
The moss covers another tower ♪
I know you are responsible.
♪ Brew iced moon springs,
the stone pot brims with sunset glows ♪
But I want you to remember
you are not alone.
♪ Wind sweeps the empty court;
writing the seasons ♪
If one day,
the sky collapses,
and you can't hold it up,
♪ When wind breaks the best tree,
the swan grows thin with grief ♪
I will.
If I can't hold it up,
♪ On the mountains, there's a monologue
in the mountains ♪
then I—
With me around,
that day will never come.
♪ Drunk in the pavilion,
vines climb up my sleeves ♪
♪ Smiling with an empty cup;
this heart is the harbor ♪
Hong Ye!
Xiao Yao!
Put me down.
♪ Cool dew freezes the day,
mist and rain veil the drifting boat ♪
Xiao Yao!
♪ Eternal night won't stay, but thankfully
there are memories to keep ♪
♪ Moon shifts stars, wind stirs
curtains at the window ♪
♪ Waiting only for a glance
from you in this lifetime ♪
A meteor shower.
It's my first time seeing one.
The stars in the sky
have fallen into chaos.
The world...
may face a great catastrophe.
What catastrophe?
The Revelation Star has shifted position.
[Chanxin Temple]
This is a sign of great calamity.
The demons inside are extraordinary.
Everyone must be careful.
Yes.
[Be Calm]
Go after him!
Yes!
You're also a demon.
Why are you helping humans?
This demon must have run too fast
and had a heart attack.
Things have been strange lately.
Great demons that are usually troublesome
keep suddenly collapsing on their own.
Whatever the reason,
it saves us
a lot of effort.
Greetings, My Lord.
It's quite a large one this time.
What's inside?
A thousand-year-old mountain demon.
Take it away.
My Lord, you must be tired.
They've been demanding
more and more live demons lately.
There are no more great demons
left near the capital.
Since His Majesty
can't drink from the Yuli Spring,
he can only use these live demons
to make elixirs
to prolong his life.
I'm merely following orders.
Only you
can speak directly with His Majesty.
His Majesty's verbal decree:
the Bulwark Duke is ordered
to report directly to the West Garden.
I, Bingzhu,
accept the decree.
Your subject
pays respects to Your Majesty.
Rise.
Have you seen the Exalted Immortal?
Did she say
how I could obtain the Yuli Spring?
Your Majesty,
she—
The Exalted Immortal,
hasn't revealed that yet.
When?
You saw her?
Just a glimpse from afar.
What did the Exalted Immortal
say?
The immortal said
Your Majesty need not worry too much.
Until I obtain the Yuli Spring,
I cannot find peace for a single day.
What exactly
does Exalted Immortal want me to do
to prove my sincerity?
My Lord.
The Elixir Refining Chamber
just reported that
today's ingredient
is barely usable.
The Chamber's requirements
are getting higher.
Ordinary demons
can no longer
meet their needs for elixir making.
However, I've received news that
Hong Ye
has returned to Demons' Valley
and is greatly weakened.
It's the perfect time to capture him.
Congratulations, My Lord.
It'll be
another great achievement for you.
I've faced Hong Ye before.
You've also been
to Demons' Valley with me.
Do you think numbers alone
would be enough to defeat him?
I was merely suggesting.
The final decision
is of course yours to make,
My Lord.
[Residence of the Bulwark Duke]
Head back.
Yes.
[Residence of the Bulwark Duke]
That mountain demon was fierce.
If you hadn't intervened,
the Feiyu Guard
would have suffered heavy losses.
Thank you.
Help me brush my hair.
Of course.
Do you see any white strands?
None at all.
As a spirit,
if I don't take human hearts,
I consume my own essence.
When did you learn to lie?
All the great demons
within close proximity
to the capital have been captured.
Next time,
let's go to Mount Qingqiu
to catch the nine-tailed fox.
Capturing demons is my duty.
You don't need to do this.
Does Master Bingzhu think
I've done something wrong?
What's yours is mine,
isn't it?
You're speaking less and less.
Are you putting your defenses up
now that I'm a spirit?
No.
I didn't understand
what Immortal Lord felt before.
But now I am starting to understand more.
Not getting love from the one you cherish,
even if you take your heart out,
the pain is still unbearable.
You can only fill the void
with others' hearts.
Now I also need human hearts.
Many, many hearts.
It's okay.
That's not it.
That's not what I think.
I just wanted to help you.
I failed to take care of you.
But I'm not who I used to be anymore.
I really don't want you
to see me like this.
While I still have my sanity,
please, you and Tan'er end this for me.
I only want you to remember Lu Pianpian,
not some heartless, cold-blooded spirit.
Please.
Why haven't you gone after Hong Ye yet?
You startled me!
This is the capital.
You're too bold!
I've waited too long!
His Maj—
It's midnight,
protect your family.
His Majesty wants to attack Hong Ye,
but Bingzhu refuses to deploy troops.
Humans and demons are different.
Court politics
are incredibly complex.
-I need to do it from various—
-Cut the crap.
Isn't the Emperor supreme among humans?
Tell him
to send troops!
If only!
If only the Emperor listens to me,
things would be easier.
I'm trying to find a solution.
I'm thinking!
Then think faster.
Have you figured it out?
Yes, I have.
That was quick.
Why don't you talk
to the Emperor yourself?
Get lost.
Don't go.
You're sending me to my death.
Let me finish.
His Majesty only wants the Yuli Spring.
He doesn't care how we get it,
right?
Since Bingzhu can't fulfill
His Majesty's wishes,
His Majesty is growing impatient.
What does this have to do with me?
If you and I
can convince the Emperor
to recognize you as the only Demon King...
The Demon King.
Go on.
This way,
humans and demons can join forces.
Whether it's eliminating enemies
or obtaining the Yuli Spring,
wouldn't everything become easier?
Humans and demons
have fought for thousands of years.
Would the Emperor agree?
Right now,
eliminating Hong Ye
is the common goal
for both you and His Majesty.
Let's go,
my Demon King.
Keep your head down. Don't look around.
Where is the emperor?
I'll go inform His Majesty right away.
Lord Heiwu,
please wait here
and don't wander off.
So luxurious.
Way too luxurious.
Ji Yan!
You lied to me!
Lord Heiwu,
I told you
not to wander off.
I'll kill you!
Look.
This is what a great demon is like.
When it burns, it's truly
extraordinary.
Keep burning.
Look.
If you don't save him now,
he'll die.
Why should I care if he dies?
He was going to send me to the Feiyu Guard
to be used as a broom.
I'm not saving him.
He used to be our teacher.
Just one.
I want to kick him.
Go ahead.
After you kick him,
give me one.
I've noticed something about you.
You're really...
I...
It fell off by itself.
Just one, okay?
You owe me a kick.
He ate it.
Xiao Yao.
Why are you being so nice to him?
This is called "taming the hawk."
"Taming the hawk"?
Why save me?
Cultivation is difficult.
It would be a waste to let it go.
Even if you save me,
no one will believe me.
I will.
You already knew Heiwu
wasn't a good master,
yet after being captured,
you only wanted to die.
Is it because of guilt?
If you can feel guilt—
so much so you want to make up for it
with your life,
someone like you
cannot be inherently evil.
Besides,
dying is the easiest thing.
But once you're dead,
you can't change anything.
People might even
whip your corpse, dig up your grave,
spit on your grave,
and you won't be able to fight back.
How frustrating would that be?
Yeah.
Can you stand such humiliation,
Mr. Wu Huan?
That makes sense.
I found it!
Xiao Yao!
Quickly call My Lord back!
My Lord, in this ancient demon record,
there's information
about the Heart-Burning Incantation.
The Heavenly Mother
used the Heart-Burning Incantation,
sealed her own power,
and then disappeared without a trace.
The stone she was standing on
witnessed the scene
and transformed into the Sky Stone.
The last time the Sky Stone appeared
was at the West Coast.
The West Coast?
What kind of place is that?
The West Coast
is guarded by an ancient beast
called the Treasure Swallower.
The Treasure Swallower
is greedy by nature.
It collects treasures from the world
and seals them in its treasury,
allowing things in but never out.
My Lord,
there's no need to worry.
I'll go for you.
For my lord,
I would die a thousand deaths.
The Treasure Swallower is no small beast.
Going there rashly
would be extremely dangerous.
The journey is long,
and you'll have
to cross the vast Western Sea.
The Western Sea has storms year-round,
with terrifying waves.
In those waters,
scaled dragons often appear.
I...
I got it.
Wait for me.
I've spoken with Wu Huan.
He's willing
to carry us to the West Coast.
My Lord, I don't believe it!
I don't believe in just these few days,
he has changed his nature.
He must be looking for an excuse
to escape when he gets the chance!
I believe him.
Wu Huan's true form is a falcon.
Like an eagle,
he is able to soar in the highest skies,
with lofty ambitions.
Before,
he was just bewitched by Heiwu.
My Lord...
Wu Huan.
Do you know
why I need to go to the West Coast?
In my battle with the Dreamshard Immortal,
I lost my power.
This trip to the West Coast
is to find
the Sky Stone that will restore my power.
My Lord,
why are you telling him this?
If I spend every day fearing betrayal
and death,
then I might as well
not be the Demon Lord.
Since I have a weakness,
rather than hiding it,
it's better that everyone knows,
so I can find other ways
to fulfill my duties as Demon Lord.
This way,
it's no longer a weakness.
Wu Huan,
this journey is extremely dangerous,
and whether I can
restore my power remains unknown.
I'm telling you all this
because I want to be an honest Demon Lord.
The same goes for you.
If you can face your past openly
and let go
of the evil thoughts in your heart,
you will still be
a pure member of the demon race.
I believe in you.
Wu Huan pays respects to My Lord.
I am willing to lay down my life for you,
in life or death.
My Lord,
even if he's willing to sacrifice himself,
with his level of power,
if he meets the Treasure Swallower
at the West Coast,
he'll die.
-It doesn't matter.
-I'm worried.
You stay in Demons' Valley.
We'll go by ourselves.
But...
My Lord!
What are you doing here?
I heard everything.
This time,
on my way back with His Lordship,
though His Lordship was injured,
he still saved me many times.
I brought some food
for Xiao Yao and His Lordship
on their journey.
The West Coast is so far away.
You'll definitely need it.
Thank you.